https://drug-rehabilitation.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy for SSH ClientsHomePrivacy Policy
Support Systems Homes is Committed to Keeping Your Protected Healthcare Information PrivateOur website address is: https://drug-rehabilitation.com.We understand that you may desire privacy regarding your treatment for substance abuse – and we’re here to make sure you are comfortable with every step of the treatment process.Data regarding participation in substance abuse treatment is protected from disclosure by state and federal law. Support Systems Homes is committed to ensuring client confidentiality and upholding all laws, regulations, and policies governing confidentiality and the protection of client records. Staff receive relevant training to ensure that they maintain the confidentiality of all clients, including records relating to their identity, and the diagnosis and treatment of substance abuse.We will only share a client’s protected information:Through written consent from the client,Among team members in the treatment setting and for utilization review, billing, and auditing purposes, orIn certain legal or medical contexts wherein it’s necessary to manage your treatment process (within HIPAA regulations, as stated below).Clients sign a form at intake indicating their understanding of the use of confidential information in day-to-day business, and that the information is protected in alignment with all laws and regulations, including information transmitted electronically.Under HIPAA regulations, you have the right to:Get a copy of your health and treatment records on request.Ask us to correct problems in your health and treatment records.Request confidential communications at any point.Ask us to limit use or sharing of any information given.Receive a list of those with whom we’ve shared your information on request.File a complaint if you feel your privacy has been violated. Visit www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/complaints/ to file a complaint.To see a more comprehensive list of your rights under HIPAA, visit: https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-individuals/guidance-materials-for-consumers/index.html.Support Systems Homes is required by law to maintain privacy for your protected health information, in accordance with HIPAA, and has safeguards in place to do so. We take the following steps to protect your personal information:Compliance with the Federal Code of Federal Regulations regarding confidentiality (CFR 42), and maintains client information in accordance with law, including keeping confidential all records relating to client identity, diagnosis, prognosis and treatmentManaging client data in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996, which details data privacy and security provisions for safeguarding medical information.Providing client information to other agencies or individuals without a specific release only in compliance with current HIPPA requirements.Such requests typically pertains to the information required by insurance companies. Data privacy safeguards are in place during transmission.Requests may pertain to information collected for evaluation, which is rendered anonymous at collection (i.e. it does not contain identifying client data).We include a copy of these requirements in our “Notice of Health Information Practices,” which every client receives a copy of during intake.Storing client records in a manner that ensures the protection of confidential informationHolding electronic data as confidential, ensuring client information stays confidential in the course of electronic transmissionsSupport Systems Homes does not sell or provide data or information gathered online, or in person, to any other entity.If you have questions about our Privacy Policy and/or your personal health information, please contact our Compliance Coordinator at 800-811-1800 or info@drug-rehabilitation.com.
